Guide to the Howard E. Buswell papers and photographs 1822-1965
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
- Pacific Northwest Historical Materials, 1946-1959; Series VIII
  - Notes on archives and manuscript collections of the Pacific Northwest, Undated (Box-folder 13/6)
  - Notes on the British Columbia Provincial Archives, including notes on a 1946 visit to the Provincial Archives, Undated (Box-folder 13/7)
  - Notes on Pacific Northwest weather, Undated (Box-folder 13/8)
  - United States District Court Records, Undated (Box-folder 13/9)
  - Port Townsend Customs Records, Undated (Box-folder 13/10)
  - Items on the San Juan Islands, Undated (Box-folder 13/11)
  - Manuscript: "The San Juan Islands" by Walbert Peterson, Undated (Box-folder 13/12)
  - The Marriage Laws of Washington, Undated (Box-folder 13/13)
  - Notes on Pacific Northwest history, Undated (Box-folder 13/14)
  - British Columbia items, Undated (Box-folder 13/15)
  - Pamphlets, Undated (Box-folder 13/16)
  - Salmon Can Labels, Undated (Box-folder 13/17)
  - Map of Alaska, 1959 (Box-folder 13/18)
  - Miscellaneous items, Undated (Box-folder 13/19)
  - Northwest American Water Boundary (photocopied Spanish, English and American maps), circa 1791-1792; 1858-1859 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Point Elliot Treaty and other treaty papers (Photostats), 1855 January 22 (Oversize-folder 1)
- Bernard N. McDonough Business Records, 1874-1913; Series IX
  - Buswell's notes on the McDonough Account Books, Undated (Box-folder 14/1)
  - Miscellaneous accounts, Undated (Box-folder 14/2)
  - Bills and Receipts, Undated (Box-folder 14/3)
  - Personal Correspondence, Undated (Box-folder 14/4)
  - Business Correspondence, Undated (Box-folder 14/5)
  - Insurance documents and papers, Undated (Box-folder 14/6)
  - Bernard N. McDonough- Army Pension Certificate, Undated (Box-folder 14/7)
  - Account Books, Undated (Box-folder 14/8)
  - Account Book (no cover), 1874-1875 (Box-folder 15/1)
  - Account Book, 1874-1876 (Box-folder 15/2)
  - Account Book, 1877-1879 (Box-folder 15/3)
  - Account Book, 1876-1881 (Box-folder 15/4)
  - Account Book, 1882-1891 (Box-folder 15/5)
  - Account Book, 1882-1884 (Box-folder 15/6)
  - Account Book, 1880 (Box-folder 16/1)
  - Account Book, 1880-1881 (Box-folder 16/2)
  - Account Book, 1881-1882 (Box-folder 16/3)
  - Account Book, 1882-1883 (Box-folder 16/4)
  - Account Book, 1883-1886 (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Account Book, 1886-1887 (Box-folder 17/2)
  - Account Book, 1889-1891 (Box-folder 17/3)
  - Account Book, 1891-1898 (Box-folder 18/1)
  - Account Book, 1898-1901 (Box-folder 18/2)
  - Account Book, 1901-1904 (Box-folder 18/3)
  - Account Book, 1877 (Box-folder 18/4)
  - Account Book, 1900-1901 (Box-folder 18a/1)
  - Account Book, 1901-1902 (Box-folder 18a/2)
  - Account Book, 1902 (Box-folder 18a/3)
  - Account Book, 1885-1913 (Box-folder 18a/4)
- Legal Documents and Papers, 1822-1925; Series X
  - Bellingham Poultry Association, Undated (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Pacific Woolgrowers Credit Corporation, Undated (Box-folder 19/2)
  - Pomona Fair Association, Whatcom County, Undated (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Aberdeen Packing Company, Undated (Box-folder 19/4)
  - Apex Fish Company, Anacortes, Undated (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Carlisle Packing Company, Lummi Island, Undated (Box-folder 19/6)
  - Carlisle Packing Company, Undated (Box-folder 19/7)
  - Carlisle Packing Company, Undated (Box-folder 19/8)
  - Carlisle Packing Company, Undated (Box-folder 19/9)
  - Exchange Fish Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 19/10)
  - Fulton Oyster and Fish Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 19/11)
  - Graham Fish Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 19/12)
  - Haro Fish Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 19/13)
  - Liberty Packing Company, Undated (Box-folder 19/14)
  - Lummi Bay Packing Company, Undated (Box-folder 19/15)
  - Lummi Rocks Fishing Company, Undated (Box-folder 19/16)
  - National Packing Company, Port Angeles, Undated (Box-folder 19/17)
  - Pacific American Fishing Company, Undated (Box-folder 19/18)
  - Puget Sound Packing Company, Fairhaven, Undated (Box-folder 19/19)
  - Puget Sound Packing Company Letterbook, 1900-1903 (Box-folder 19/20)
  - San Juan Fishing and Packing Company, Seattle, Undated (Box-folder 20/1)
  - Shaw Island Canning Company, Shaw Island, Undated (Box-folder 20/2)
  - Miscellaneous lumber leases, Whatcom County, Undated (Box-folder 20/3)
  - Materials concerning log booms, Undated (Box-folder 20/4)
  - A-P Shingle Company (originally Windsor Park Shingle Company), Undated (Box-folder 20/5)
  - Bellingham Bay Boom Company, Undated (Box-folder 20/6)
  - Bellingham Bay Shingle and Lumber Company, Undated (Box-folder 20/7)
  - Bertram Shingle Company, Lynden, Undated (Box-folder 20/8)
  - Burpee Brothers Company, Anacortes, Undated (Box-folder 20/9)
  - Clearbrook Lumber Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 20/10)
  - Cleaves-Dickerson Company, Whatcom County, Undated (Box-folder 20/11)
  - Clipper Shingle Company, Undated (Box-folder 20/12)
  - Cody Shingle Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 20/13)
  - Custer Shingle Company, Undated (Box-folder 20/14)
  - Enterprise Mill Company, Ferndale, Undated (Box-folder 20/15)
  - Excelsior Lumber Company, Ferndale, Undated (Box-folder 20/16)
  - Gilt Edge Shingle Company, Undated (Box-folder 20/17)
  - Guaranty Lumber Company, Noon's Station, Whatcom County, Undated (Box-folder 20/18)
  - Homestead Shingle Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 20/19)
  - Kahlar-Bell Shingle Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 20/20)
  - Marietta Shingle Company, Undated (Box-folder 20/21)
  - Carl Miller Lumber Company, Undated (Box-folder 20/22)
  - Miller-Kinyon Shingle Company, Undated (Box-folder 20/23)
  - Modern Shingle Company, Custer, Undated (Box-folder 20/24)
  - Mogul Logging Company, Whatcom County, Undated (Box-folder 20/25)
  - National Mill Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 20/26)
  - Pacific Fir Company, Seattle, Undated (Box-folder 20/27)
  - Parker Shingle Mill Company, Blaine, Undated (Box-folder 20/28)
  - Pillsbury and Cleaves Brothers Shingle Company, Ten Mile, Whatcom County, Undated (Box-folder 20/29)
  - Red Cedar Shingle Manufacturers' Association, Seattle, Undated (Box-folder 20/30)
  - Reull Shingle Mill, Whatcom County, Undated (Box-folder 20/31)
  - Ritchie-Shelton Lumber Company, Whatcom County, Undated (Box-folder 20/32)
  - Rollins and Adams Shingle Company, Whatcom County, Undated (Box-folder 20/33)
  - Union Manufacturing Company, New Whatcom, Undated (Box-folder 20/34)
  - Valley Shingle Company, Lake Padden, Undated (Box-folder 20/35)
  - Walker Shingle Company, Lawrence, Undated (Box-folder 20/36)
  - West Coast Timber Company, Undated (Box-folder 20/37)
  - Whatcom Timber Company, Undated (Box-folder 20/38)
  - Wyatt and Miller Lumber Company, Undated (Box-folder 20/39)
  - Miscellaneous mining papers, Undated (Box-folder 20/40)
  - Mining leases and indentures, Undated (Box-folder 20/41)
  - Alaska Drilling and Mining Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 20/42)
  - Bellingham Bay Coal Company, Sehome, Undated (Box-folder 20/43)
  - Bellingham Coal Mines Company, Undated (Box-folder 20/44)
  - Bellingham National Gas Company, Undated (Box-folder 20/45)
  - Bellingham Placer Mining Company, Undated (Box-folder 20/46)
  - Galena Mining Company, Whatcom County, Undated (Box-folder 20/47)
  - Gold Sea Mining Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 20/48)
  - Hoosier Mining Company, Seattle, Undated (Box-folder 21/1)
  - Hoosier Mining Co. Share Certificate Register, 1902-1906 (Box-folder 21/2)
  - Nooksack Bend Oil Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 21/3)
  - Northwest Oil and Gas Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 21/4)
  - Olympic Portland Cement Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 21/5)
  - Olympic Portland Cement Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 21/6)
  - Swift Creek Mining and Smelting Company, New Whatcom, Undated (Box-folder 21/7)
  - Swift Creek Mining and Smelting Company, New Whatcom, Undated (Box-folder 21/8)
  - Twin Sisters Mining Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 21/9)
  - Fawcett Brothers Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 21/10)
  - Pioneer Livery and Transfer Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 21/11)
  - Bellingham Tug and Barge Company, Bellingham, Undated (Box-folder 21/12)
  - Lynden Electric Motor Railway Company, Undated (Box-folder 21/13)
  - Lynden Electric Railway and Improvement Company, Undated (Box-folder 21/14)
  - Canfield-Caulkins Implement Co., Undated (Box-folder 21/15)
  - Materials regarding Edmund A. Smith's Fish Cleaning Machine Patent, 1905 (Box-folder 21/16)
  - Seattle and Montana Railroad Company, Undated (Box-folder 22/1)
  - Silver Lake Telephone Company Articles of Incorporation, Undated (Box-folder 22/2)
  - Sumas Electric Light Company, Undated (Box-folder 22/3)
  - The Whatcom Rochdale Company, Undated (Box-folder 22/4)
  - Thomas Kelley and William T. Hatton: articles of co-partnership, Undated (Box-folder 22/5)
  - Whatcom County: miscellaneous items on companies, Undated (Box-folder 22/6)
  - Puget Sound Loan, Trust, and Banking Company, Undated (Box-folder 22/7)
  - Sample Stock Certificates, Undated (Box-folder 22/8)
  - U.S. Circuit Court, Northern Division Case #163: United States vs. Bellingham Bay Boom Co., 1895 June 13 (Box-folder 22/9)
  - U.S. Circuit Court, Northern Division Case #292: United States vs. The Skagit Boom Company, 1894 June 19 (Box-folder 22/10)
  - U.S. Circuit Court Case #626: John W. Lynch vs. the Steamer "Cascade", 1893 June (Box-folder 22/11)
  - U.S. Circuit Court Case #636: Charles O'Brien, et al, vs. the Barque "McNear", 1893 August (Box-folder 22/12)
  - U.S. Circuit Court Case #636: Charles O'Brien, et al, vs. the Barque "McNear" Testimony, 1893 August (Box-folder 22/13)
  - U.S. District Court Case #648: William S. Pulver vs. the Steamer "San Juan", 1893 September 27 (Box-folder 22/14)
  - United States District Court, Northern Division Case #26: William Munks vs. the Steamer "Susie", 1883 August 11 (Box-folder 22/15)
  - United States District Court, Northern Division Case #660: Chris Paulson et al. vs the Steamer-Tug "Mystic", Testimony, 1893 September 25 (Box-folder 23/1)
  - United States District Court, Northern Division Case #661: W.B. Seymour vs. the Steamer "Ellis", Commissioner's Report of Testimony, 1893 September 13 (Box-folder 23/2)
  - United States District Court, Northern Division Case #675: S. Saunders, et al. vs the Steamer "Ellis", 1893 October 13 (Box-folder 23/3)
  - United States District Court, Northern Division Case # ?: George Nolte and Charles Nolte vs. the Steamer "Island Belle", 1893 December 7 (Box-folder 23/4)
  - United States District Court, Northern Division Case #755: Bellingham Bay Iron Works vs. the Steamer "Brick", 1894 May 23 (Box-folder 23/5)
  - United States District Court, Northern Division Case #755: Bellingham Bay Iron Works vs. the Steamer "Brick", Time Book, 1894 May 23 (Box-folder 23/6)
  - United States District Court, Northern Division Case #764: E.E. Libby, et al. vs. the Steamer "Buckeye", 1894 May 17 (Box-folder 23/7)
  - United States District Court, Northern Division Case #764: E.E. Libby, et al. vs. the Steamer "Buckeye", Ledgers, 1894 May 24 (Box-folder 23/8)
  - United States District Court, Northern Division Case #1768: R.E. Gibbon, et al. vs. the Steamer "Newsboy", 1901 August 2 (Box-folder 24/1)
  - United States District Court, Northern Division Case #1768: R.E. Gibbon, et al. vs. the Steamer "Newsboy", Testimony and Evidence, 1901 August 2 (Box-folder 24/2)
  - United States District Court, Northern Division Case #1079: Puget Sound Sawmill and Shingle Co. vs. Pacific American Fisheries Company, 1904 October 1 (Box-folder 24/3)
  - United States District Court, Northern Division Case #1079: Puget Sound Sawmill and Shingle Co. vs. Pacific American Fisheries Company, Receiver's Report, 1905 November 4 (Box-folder 24/4)
  - United States Circuit Court Case #2011: United States vs. L.J. Sennes, 1911 August 18 (Box-folder 24/5)
  - United States Circuit Court Case #2011: United States vs. L.J. Sennes, 1911 August 18 (Box-folder 24/6)
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals, Ninth Circuit, Case #3153: United States vs. J.W. Romaine, 1919 January 6 (Box-folder 24/7)
  - United States District Court/United States Commissioners' Court Case #643: United States vs. C.F. Swan, 1893 June 13 (Box-folder 24/8)
  - Miscellaneous legal papers concerning the state of Alabama, 1822-1866 (Box-folder 25/1)
  - Territory of Washington vs. Abner Dunn, Justice of the Peace transcripts, 1862 October 22 (Box-folder 25/2)
  - Superior Court, Skagit County, Munks vs. Munks, Undated (Box-folder 25/3)
  - Whatcom Co. Superior Court: Marianne C. Windsor vs. Andrew J. Pence, 1900 May 26 (Box-folder 25/4)
  - Whatcom County vs. James Yellowkanim, 1906 July 6 (Box-folder 25/5)
  - Whatcom Co. Superior Court Case # 746: State of Washington vs. R.F. Walker, Extracts of Testimony, 1907 September 24 (Box-folder 25/6)
  - Whatcom Co. Superior Court Case # 746: State of Washington vs. R.F. Walker, Testimony, 1907 September 24 (Box-folder 25/7)
  - Whatcom Co. Superior Court Case # 10752: A.E. Mead vs. John Heber and wife, 1913 July (Box-folder 25/8)
  - Whatcom Co. Superior Court: C.S. Packard vs. W.G. Peters, 1914 December 30 (Box-folder 25/9)
  - Washington State Supreme Court Case # 11686: George Trigg, et al. vs. Charlie F. and E. Tinkerman, Undated (Box-folder 25/10)
  - Whatcom Co. Superior Court Case # 11716: Whatcom County vs. A.J. Zane, et al, 1915 January 9 (Box-folder 25/11)
  - Whatcom Co. Superior Court Case # 11716: Whatcom County vs. A.J. Zane, et al, 1915 January (Box-folder 25/12)
  - Whatcom Co. Superior Court Case #13800: J.W. Tarte and wife vs. J.A. Edson and wife, 1919 February 26 (Box-folder 25/13)
  - An Act for the Repealing an Act of the 12th Year of King George III, 1792, Undated (Box-folder 25/14)
  - Court Documents concerning Hazard Stevens, 1873-1891 (Box-folder 26/1)
  - Deeds and Indentures concerning George and Lydia Foster, 1882-1891 (Box-folder 26/2)
  - Deeds and Indentures concerning James Buckley, 1882-1891 (Box-folder 26/3)
  - Indentures and Receipts concering Bailey Gatzert, 1882-1890 (Box-folder 26/4)
  - Abstract of Title, Tillamook, Oregon, 1914 June (Box-folder 26/5)
  - Abstract of Title, Whatcom County, WA., 1909 (Box-folder 26/6)
  - Abstract of Title, Whatcom County, WA., 1911 (Box-folder 26/7)
  - Abstract of Title, Whatcom County, WA., 1908 (Box-folder 26/8)
  - Abstract of Title, Whatcom County, WA., 1896-1905 (Box-folder 26/9)
  - Abstract of Title, Whatcom County, WA., Undated (Box-folder 26/10)
  - Abstract of Title, Whatcom County, WA., 1902 (Box-folder 26/11)
  - Abstract of Title, Whatcom County, WA., 1908 (Box-folder 26/12)
  - Abstract of Title, Whatcom County, WA., 1905 (Box-folder 26/13)
  - Abstract of Title, Bellingham Bay Land Company's 2nd Addition to Bellingham, 1902 (Box-folder 26/14)
  - Abstract of Title, Eldridge's Addition to Bellingham, 1870 (Box-folder 26/15)
  - Abstract of Title, Fairhaven Block 44, 1890 (Box-folder 26/16)
  - Abstract of Title, 1st Addition to Fairhaven, 1902 (Box-folder 26/17)
  - Abstract of Title, New Ferndale Block 2, 1894 (Box-folder 26/18)
  - Abstract of Title, Fort Bellingham Land, 1879 (Box-folder 26/19)
  - Abstract of Title, Eldridge's Addition to Marietta, 1890 (Box-folder 27/1)
  - Abstract of Title, Canfield's Addition to Marietta, 1918 (Box-folder 27/2)
  - Abstract of Title, 1st Addition to New Whatcom, 1889 (Box-folder 27/3)
  - Abstract of Title, New Whatcom Block 148 according to the "Whatcom County Tide Land Appraiser's Map of New Whatcom Tide Lands", 1891 (Box-folder 27/4)
  - Abstract of Title, Jamieson's Bay View Addition, Sehome Block 11, 1891 (Box-folder 27/5)
  - Abstract of Title, Silver Beach Plat Block 4, 1890 (Box-folder 27/6)
  - Abstract of Title, Eldridge's 1st Addition, Whatcom, 1900 (Box-folder 27/7)
  - Abstract of Title, Garden Addition, Whatcom, 1920 (Box-folder 27/8)
  - Abstract of Title, Whatcom Block 195 according to the "Supplemental Map of Whatcom", 1886 (Box-folder 27/9)
  - Land Sale Agreement between James Seclamatan and G.J. Polinder, 1908 (Box-folder 27/10)
  - Declaration of Homestead made by Sam Olson of Van Zandt, 1903 (Box-folder 27/11)
  - Land Law Dissertation, Undated (Box-folder 27/12)
  - Whatcom County Indentures, Undated (Box-folder 27/13)
  - Whatcom County Leases and Mortgages, Undated (Box-folder 27/14)
  - Whatcom County Agreements, 1906-1915 (Box-folder 27/15)
  - Affadavits, Undated (Box-folder 27/16)
  - Notices to Vacate, 1903-1915 (Box-folder 27/17)
  - Wills and Executor Documents, 1880-1925 (Box-folder 27/18)
  - Letter from Senator S.M. Piles to Hurlbut and Nicholson including copies of three U.S. Senate Bills, 1909 January 13 (Box-folder 27/19)
- Scrapbooks, 1941-1965; Series XI
  - Scrapbook 'A', Natural History, Science, History, etc., Undated (Box-folder 28/1)
  - Scrapbook 'B', Natural History, etc., Undated (Box-folder 28/2)
  - Scrapbook 'C', Natural History, History, Indian Lore, etc., Undated (Box-folder 28/3)
  - Scrapbook 'D', History: Natural, Pre-, B.C. to A.D., Local, Geology, Anthropology, etc., Undated (Box-folder 28/4)
  - Scrapbook 'E', 50 Years of Progress, Undated (Box-folder 28/5)
  - Scrapbook 'E2', Mrs. Roeder's Funeral, Undated (Box-folder 28/6)
  - Scrapbook 'F', Museum Notes 1941 and Miscellaneous Science, Undated (Box-folder 28/7)
  - Scrapbook 'F', Lummi Indian Tribe Clippings and Some Trivia, Undated (Box-folder 28/8)
  - Scrapbook 'G', Whatcom County History, Undated (Box-folder 28/9)
  - Scrapbook 'H', Whatcom County and Washington State Pioneer History, Undated (Box-folder 28/10)
  - Scrapbook 'I', General Washington State History, Undated (Box-folder 28/11)
  - Scrapbook 'J', Whatcom County History, Undated (Box-folder 28/12)
  - Scrapbook 'K', Whatcom County History and World Events, Undated (Box-folder 29/1)
  - Scrapbook 'L', World War II and Whatcom County History, Undated (Box-folder 29/2)
  - Scrapbook 'M', World's Largest Christmas Tree and Whatcom County History, Undated (Box-folder 29/3)
  - Scrapbook 'N', Whatcom County History, Sea Pioneers, World's Largest Christmas Tree, Undated (Box-folder 29/4)
  - Scrapbook 'O', Whatcom County History, Lummi Indian Tribe, Undated (Box-folder 29/5)
  - Scrapbook 'P', Washington State History, Washington Names, Undated (Box-folder 29/6)
  - Unlabeled Scrapbook, Whatcom County History, Undated (Box-folder 29/7)
  - Bellingham to Washington, D.C. Scrapbook, Trip Memorabilia, Undated (Box-folder 29/8)
  - Unlabeled Scrapbook, 'The Story of Enterprise' from the Ferndale Record, 1965 (Box-folder 29/9)
  - Unlabeled Scrapbook, Clippings of Poetry, Stories, Language, Undated (Box-folder 29/10)
  - Biographical Clippings and Trivia Scrapbook, Undated (Box-folder 29/11)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1891-1975; Series XII
  - Various newspaper clippings from the Bellingham Herald, Seattle Times, Seattle Star, and the Seattle Sunday Times Magazine as well as other publications, 1891-1975 (Box 30)
    (Clippings are mostly concerned with Pacific Northwest History and Whatcom County History.)
- Microfilm, 1865-1946; Series XIII
  - Whatcom County Commissioner's Reports - Book I, Undated (Reel 1)
  - Whatcom County Commissioner's Reports- Book II, Undated (Reel 2)
  - Whatcom County Commissioner's Reports - Book III, Undated (Reel 3)
  - Whatcom County Commissioner's Reports - Book IV, Undated (Reel 4)
  - Indian War Pension Claims, Undated (Reel 5)
  - "Topographical Memoir of the Department of the Pacific", 1865 (Reel 6)
  - Blaine Journal, 1889-1890 (Reel 6)
  - Bellingham Bay Express, 1892 August 11 (Reel 6)
  - "Speculi Britanniae Pars. A Topographical Historical Description of Cornwall by John Norden", from the British Museum, Undated (Reel 7)
  - Census Reports for Lummi Reservation, 1885-1937 (Reel 8)
  - Census Reports for Lummi Reservation, 1886-1912 (Reel 9)
  - Lummi School Rolls, 1906 (Reel 9)
  - Whatcom County Post Office Records #28 - Records of Appointment of Postmasters and Site Locator Reports, 1857-1946 (Reel 10)
- Audio Collection, 1956-1964; Series XIV
  - Mrs. John Brown, 1960 January 15 (Reel-to-reel Reel #1)
    Howard E. Buswell: This is January the 15th 1960. About the third of the way through this reel of tape is a tape of a religious discourse by the late Mrs. John Brown. Formerly Mrs. Johanna Guerin. I believe her maiden name was Johanna Ti'elish. Or Johanna George Ti'elish. I just played it over after a lapse of several years since Mrs. Brown and her husband John have been dead for two or three years now, and I found it of considerable interest. I meant this in the fact that there is an unoccupied piece of tape for quite a ways. After Mrs. Brown's discourse is a sermon. And other services at the Marietta Mission. It is run by the Reverend and Mrs. Walter Harnden. The Mormons that continue on the religious, the religion of the Lummi people, the Mormons have a mission here in the house formerly occupied and owned by Mr. Chris Iyland. I do not believe, besides the Mormons, and Reverend Harnden's Mission, that there are any other active religious groups on the reservation except the Roman Catholics, who have had a church there for many years. But in the past decades or two why various Protestant groups have come in, but none of them have seem to have shown the stick-to-itiveness that the Mormons and Reverend Harnden's Mission have. The Shaker's have a church over there, but I don't believe it is being used now. Mrs. Brown was a very devout Christian woman. She and her husband use to go to the Catholic Church, but they for some reason or another, they found that they were not getting what they wanted. So they turned their backs on it, and became followers of revivalists such as Oral Roberts. Mrs. Brown always went to his revivals meetings when he was in the area. And she is telling in her discourse here, something about her observations and experiences of while he was having his services. I don't know whether it was in Portland, Oregon or Tacoma. But somewhere within easy traveling distance of this location.
    Cassette Tape # 1: Mrs. John Brown (Johanna Guerin/Ti'elish) recounts her observations of the healings and miracles she has witnessed through prayer. She calls this, "to lay hands on the sick." She then reads a letter she received from Oral Roberts, an evangelical preacher. Following this she reads or preaches from memory a sermon based on Bible scriptures. She, throughout, emphasizes the healing miracles she has witnessed by Oral Roberts. One example is an Indian man, she recalls from Neah Bay who was healed. The interview segways into a broadcast of Oral Roberts entitled the "Indian Christian Hour" which appeared on KVOS.
    Cassette Tape #2: Oral Roberts' TV program continues. Many hymns are sung (in English). Indian people are asked to come forward and give their testimony. A service by Rev. Harnden follows given at the Marietta Indian Mission. Rev. Harnden notes: "Don't be called among those, a rebellious people."
  - Philip Clark and John Nichols, undated (Reel-to-reel Reel #2)